规范是团队合作的关键。
Specifications are the linchpin of teamwork.
想把责任下放是不可能的
It's impossible to think about delegating responsibility
用于实现方法，除非您有明确的规范
for implementing a method unless you have a clear specification
作为合同。
that acts as a contract.
执行者负责履行合同，
Implementer's responsible for meeting that contract,
以及使用该方法的客户端
and a client that uses the method
可以信赖那个合同。
can rely on that contract.
事实上，我们会看到像真正的法律合同一样，
In fact, we'll see that like real legal contracts,
规格对双方都有要求。
specifications place demands on both parties.
规格可以有
The specification can have can have
先决条件，将责任推给客户。
a precondition, which puts the responsibility on the client.
在这篇文章中，我们将讨论角色
In this reading, we're going to look at the roles
方法规范发挥作用。
that method specifications play.
我们将讨论什么先决条件
We're going to talk about what preconditions
后置条件是什么意思
and postconditions are and what they mean
对于实现者和客户。
for implementers and clients.
我们还将讨论如何使用异常
We'll also talk about how to use exceptions, which
是一个非常重要的语言特征
are a very important language feature that's
不仅可以在Java中找到，在Python中也可以找到
found not only in Java, but also in Python
以及其他现代语言，使我们能够
and other modern languages that allow us to make a method's
界面更安全，更容易理解。
interface safer from bugs and easier to understand.
那么为什么要制定规范呢？
So why specifications?
程序中最讨厌的错误出现了
The nastiest bugs in programs arise
因为对行为的误解
because of misunderstandings about behavior
在接口处，调用方之间
at the interface, between the caller
一个代码和实现，
of a code and the implementation,
函数的调用与实现
the call of the function and the implementation
这一功能。
of that function.
现在每个人都有一个规范
Now everybody has a specification
考虑到一个函数应该如何运行，
in mind about how, let's say, a function should behave,
但并不是每个人都写下来。
but not everybody actually writes them down.
因此，团队中的不同程序员
As a result, different programmers on the team
可能有不同的规格。
might have different specifications in mind.
所以当程序失败的时候，很难准确地找出
So when the program fails, it's hard to figure out exactly
该怪哪部分代码。
which part of the code is to blame.
所以写下这些精确的规格
So writing down these precise specs
可以让你知道你应该把你的修复。
can let you figure out where you should put your fix.
规范对方法的客户机也有好处
Specs are also good for the client of a method
因为他们不让客户真正阅读
because they spare the client the task of actually reading
密码。
the code.
下面是Java库中的一个例子，
And here's an example of that from part of the Java library,
事实上。
actually.
这是BigInteger类中的add方法
So this is the add method from the BigInteger class
这就是它的规格描述
and this is what its spec looks like-- describes
它的参数类型是什么
what the types are of its arguments
它说明了它的实际功能。
and it says what it actually does.
它非常，非常短而且容易理解。
And it's very, very short and easy to understand.
如果我们没有那个规格，我们
Now if we didn't have that spec, we
可能得去看看路
might have to actually go and look at the way
该功能已实现。
that function is implemented.
实际上，所有的Java库函数
In fact, all the Java library functions
他们的消息来源在网上，所以我们可以去看看，
do have their source online, so we can go and look at it,
但这更难理解。
but this is far more difficult to understand.
事实上，如果我们想理解它，
And in fact, if we wanted to understand it,
我们不仅要读这个，还可以
we'd have to not only read this, but we might also
必须看看构造器实际做了什么，
have to look at what the constructor actually does,
这些辅助函数的功能——比较大小和相减，
what these helper functions-- compare magnitude and subtract,
而且可信的带前导零整数。
and trusted strip leading zero ints do.
可能有很多代码需要我们去挖掘
There might be lots of code that we have to dig through in order
找出这个函数的实际行为。
to figure out actually what the behavior of this function is.
把它和阅读这个简单的高层描述结合起来。
Pair that with just reading this simple high level description.
最后，规范对于方法的实现者是有好处的
Finally, specs are good for the implementer of a method
因为他们给了实施者改变的自由
because they give the implementer freedom to change
在没有告诉客户的情况下实施，
the implementation without even telling the clients,
完全不改变客户端代码。
without changing the client code at all.
这实际上意味着规范可以使代码更快。
And that actually means specs can make code faster.
有时会有一个弱规范
Sometimes by having a weak specification that
留下一些模糊的东西
leaves vague some of the things that the function might
在某些情况下，你可以选择
do in some circumstances, you can choose a much more
有效实施。
efficient implementation.
特殊前提——记住
Particular precondition-- remember
这是客户的条件--可能排除
that's a condition that's on the client-- may rule out
某些状态，某些方法，你可以调用
certain states, certain ways you might call a method that would
强迫你，强迫实施者
have forced you, forced the implementer
做一些昂贵的支票
to make some kind of expensive check
那已经没有必要了。
that's no longer necessary.
我们将在后面的阅读中看到一些例子。
And we'll see some examples of that later in this reading.
所以有一种方法可以让你思考什么是规范
So one way you can think about what a specification is
它是客户端和实现者之间的防火墙。
is that it's a firewall between the client and the implementer.
它保护客户不受工作细节的影响
It shields the client from the details of the workings
执行情况。
of the implementation.
你不必真的去读
You don't have to actually read the source
程序的代码（如果您有它的规范）。
code of the procedure if you have its spec.
它保护实现者不受细节的影响
And it shields the implementer from the details
客户将如何使用它。
of how the clients are going to use it.
实现者不必询问每个客户机
The implementer doesn't have to ask every client
他们计划如何使用这个单位。
how they plan to use the unit.
所以这个防火墙，这个想法，结果
So this firewall, this idea, results
在这两段代码的分离中
in a decoupling between these two pieces of code
允许单位代码和客户代码
that allow the code of the unit and the code of the client
独立地改变，只要这些改变尊重
to be changed independently, as long as those changes respect
本规范及双方均遵守其义务。
this specification and each side obeys its obligation.
让我们认真考虑一下这个想法
Let's get down to brass tacks and think about the idea
行为对等。
of behavioral equivalence.
这里有两种方法，先找到后找到。
Here are two methods, find first and find last.
它们都取一个整数数组
Both of them take an array of integers
一个特定的整数值和搜索
and a particular integer value and search
对于数组中的那个值。
for that value in the array.
然后他们返回阵地，
And then they return the position,
在数组中找到的值的索引。
the index of the value if it's found in the array.
当然，这两个的代码是不同的，
Now, of course, the code for these two is different,
所以在这个意义上，它们是不同的。
so in that sense, they're different.
我们给他们起了不同的名字
And we've actually given them different names just
所以我们可以谈谈他们
so we can talk about them, so they're
在这方面不同。
different in that respect.
但让我们想想他们的行为。
But let's think about their behavior.
为了确定行为等效性，
To determine behavior equivalence,
问题是我们是否可以替换一个实现
the question is whether we can substitute one implementation
对于另一个，不必更改使用它的代码。
for the other without having to change the code that uses it.
现在这两种方法，
Now these two methods, turns out,
在某些情况下确实有不同的行为。
do actually have different behavior in some situations.
所以当在数组中根本找不到val时，这两种情况下，
So when val isn't found in the array at all, both cases,
此循环将无法成功找到--
this loop will not successfully find--
它将穿过整个阵列。
it will go through the whole array.
然后find first将返回数组的长度
And then find first will return the length of the array
最后一个将返回负数。
and find last will return negative one.
顺便说一下，这两个索引都是无效的
Both of these, by the way, are invalid indexes and that's
这些方法试图通过返回它们来做什么。
what these methods are trying to do by returning them.
但它们在不同方面是无效的。
But they're invalid in different ways.
这个在数组的末尾
This one is off the end of the array
这个在数组开始之前。
and this one is before the start of the array.
还有别的案子
There's another case or other cases
他们表现不同的地方。
where they behave differently.
当val出现不止一次时，则
When val appears more than once, then
先找到威尔——因为它在移动
find first will-- because it's moving
从头到尾穿过数组--
through the array from start to end--
它会发现第一次出现val
it will find the first occurrence of val
并返回索引。
and return the index for that.
而find last，因为它从数组的末尾开始，
Whereas find last, because it's going from the end of array,
最终会找到该值的最后一次出现
will end up finding the last occurrence of that value
把它还给我。
and return that.
所以他们有不同的方式，
So there are ways in which they're different,
但也有一种关键的[听不见的]方式
but there's also this crucial [INAUDIBLE] way
它们是一样的。
in which they're the same.
当val在数组中恰好出现一次时，
When val occurs exactly once in the array,
这两种方法的行为完全相同。
these two methods behave exactly the same.
它们在索引中返回它发生的位置。
They return in the index where it occurs.
可能是客户从不依赖这种行为
And it may be the clients never rely on the behavior
其他的案子。
of those other cases.
每当他们调用该方法时，客户机
Whenever they call the method, the clients
确定他们会在数组中传递
are certain they're going to be passing in an array
只出现一个val，只有一个元素
with exactly one occurrence of val, exactly one element that
匹配val。
matches val.
对于这样的客户，这些方法是一样的，
For clients like that, these methods are the same,
我们可以从一个实现切换到另一个实现
and we can switch from one implementation to the other
没有任何问题。
without any issue.
所以行为对等的概念
So the notion of behavioral equivalence
在旁观者的眼中，在使用者的眼中，
really is in the eye of the beholder, in the user,
在客户那里。
in the client.
为了使替代成为可能
In order to make it possible to substitute
一个实现另一个，我们可能需要
one implementation for the other, which we might want
根据性能或修复错误，
to do, depending on performance or fixing bugs,
我们想知道什么时候可以接受。
we want to know when this is acceptable.
所以我们需要一个说明
So we need a specification that states
正是这些客户所依赖的
exactly what these clients depend on
使实施者有自由
so that the implementer has the freedom
做那个替代品。
to make that substitution.
所以在这种情况下，我们可以编写这个规范。
So in this case, we might write this specification.
上面说客户必须保证val
It says that the client has to guarantee that the val will
在数组中只出现一次，如果是这样，
occur exactly once in the array, and when that's true,
它的作用是返回那个索引。
the effect of it will be to return the index of that.
在接下来的规范中，这两个
And in what we do next with this specification, these two
代码片段——这两个实现
pieces of code-- these two implementations
find函数的
of the find function-- would be equivalent
而实施者也有权这样做
and the implementer would have the freedom to do it either
太好了。
way.
所以在下一部分，我们要谈谈
So in the next part, we're going to talk
关于这些要求和影响条款的实际含义。
about what these requires and affects clauses actually mean.